Joy Kwamboka

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

kwambokaj2.jk@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio | +254711607261

SUMMARY

I am a Full-Stack Web developer, an avid Open-Source enthusiast with adept collaborative skills and a strong understanding of web design. Well-versed in front and back-end development languages, frameworks, and libraries to optimize the user experience.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

March 2022 - Present

Restaurant App — The website displays different meal categories and one can like or comment on the specific category.

- Built with: Vanilla JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Git version control, GitHub
- Repository link: Source Code

Budget Checker - A simple website that enables one to monitor their expenditure by listing the shops and the items they have spent money on.

- Built with: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS3, Git version control, GitHub, Heroku
- Repository link: Source Code

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

April 2022 - October 2022

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

STATE DEPARTMENT OF LIVESTOCK

Nairobi, Kenya

Statistician

January 2020 - March 2022

- Developed a WordPress website to create awareness and also built a data collection tool for the collection of Livestock data all over the country.
- Acted as a focal contact point, facilitating communication between the various stakeholders for the Kenya Livestock Master Plan.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

March 2022 - October, 2022

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

TAITA TAVETA UNIVERSITY

September 2015 - April 2019

BSc in Mathematics and Computer Science; major in Statistics

Spent 4 years learning computer Systems and Security, and programming languages, among others.